Get ready to hit the road!
Toy Story 4 is a family, comedy, animation film directed by Josh Cooley.
Woody has always been confident about his place in the world and that his
priority is taking care of his kid, whether that's Andy or Bonnie.
But when Bonnie adds a reluctant new toy called "Forky" to her room, a road trip adventure
alongside old and new friends will show Woody how big the world can be for a toy.
Woody (voice), played by Tom Hanks.
Buzz Lightyear (voice), played by Tim Allen.
Bo Peep (voice), played by Annie Potts.
Forky (voice), played by Tony Hale.
Ducky (voice), played by Keegan-Michael Key.
Bonnie (voice), played by Madeleine McGraw.
Toy Story 4 is a 2019 American animated comedy film produced by
Pixar Animation Studios for Walt Disney Pictures.
It is the fourth  installment in Pixar's Toy Story film
series and the sequel to Toy Story 3 (2010).
It was directed by Josh Cooley from a screenplay by Andrew Stanton and Stephany Folsom; the three also developed the
story alongside John Lasseter, Rashida Jones, Will McCormack, Valerie LaPointe, and Martin Hynes.
Tom Hanks, Tim Allen, Annie Potts, Don Rickles, Wallace Shawn, John Ratzenberger, Blake Clark, Jeff Pidgeon, Laurie Metcalf, John Morris,  Joan Cusack, and Estelle Harris are among the actors who reprise
their character roles from the first three films, and are joined by Tony Hale, Keegan-Michael Key, Jordan Peele, Christina Hendricks, Keanu Reeves, and Ally Maki, who voice new characters.
Set after the third film, Toy Story 4 follows Woody (Hanks) and Buzz Lightyear (Allen) as the pair and the other toys go on a
road trip with Bonnie (McGraw), who creates Forky (Hale), a spork made with recycled materials from her school.
Meanwhile, Woody is reunited with Bo Peep (Potts), and
must decide where his loyalties lie.
Talks for a fourth Toy Story film began in 2010, and Hanks
stated that Pixar was working on the film in 2011.
When the film was officially announced in November 2014 during an investor's call, it was reported that the film would be directed by Lasseter, who later announced it would
be a love story, after writing a film treatment with Stanton, and input from Pete Docter and Lee Unkrich, while Galyn Susman would serve as the producer.
Cooley was announced as the film's co-director in March 2015, while Pixar president Jim Morris described
the film as a romantic comedy and said it would not be a continuation of the third film.
In 2016, Cooley replaced Lasseter as the film's new director.
New characters for the film were announced in 2018
and 2019 along with new cast members.
Composer Randy Newman returned to score the film,
marking his ninth collaboration with Pixar.
Toy Story 4 premiered in Hollywood, Los Angeles, on June 11, 2019,
and was released in the United States on June 21.
It grossed $1.074 billion worldwide, becoming the eighth-highest-grossing film of 2019 and is
the highest-grossing film in the franchise, marginally surpassing Toy Story 3.
Like its predecessors, the film received acclaim from critics, with praise for its story,
humor, emotional depth, musical score, animation, and vocal performances.
The film was nominated for two awards at the 92nd Academy Awards, winning
Best Animated Feature, and received numerous other accolades.
A sequel, Toy Story 5, is scheduled to be released on June 19, 2026.
The film explores themes of friendship, cartoon,
rescue mission, sequel, anti villain.
The tone is lighthearted.